

DEEPAK KUMAR PALAI

CONTACT

Mumbai, 400063

8657195738

deepakpalai33@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Business development
- · Employee training
- · Business networking
- Branch audit experience
- · Staff mentoring
- Staff management
- · Financial product understanding
- Staff recruitment
- Customer relationship management systems
- Sales strategy development
- Time management efficiency
- Stakeholder communications
- Client Relationship Management

LANGUAGES

Hindi:	C2
Proficient	
English:	B2
Upper Intermediate	
ORIYA:	C2
Proficient	

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 30/06/1988 Nationality: INDIAN Marital status: BACHELOR

Gender: MALE

SUMMARY

Experienced in overseeing daily operations and driving team performance to achieve business goals. Excels in customer relationship management and implementing strategic initiatives to enhance branch profitability. Committed to fostering positive work environment and continuous improvement.

EXPERIENCE

Branch Manager, 06/2024 - Current

L&G Insurance - Mumbai, India

- Developed and implemented strategies to increase sales and profitability within the branch.
- Prepared and presented reports on branch performance, trends, and forecasts to senior management.
- Conducted regular staff meetings to communicate targets, performance expectations, and company updates.
- Streamlined operational processes through the integration of new technology and systems.
- Fostered a positive working environment, promoting teamwork and employee satisfaction.

Corporate Sales Manager, 10/2022 - 04/2024 HDFC Life Insurance - Mumbai, India

- Managed a team of eight people, covering 8+ HDFC branches for retail sales, to ensure progress. Assigned territories to the team, and updated daily, weekly, and monthly reports for senior leadership as needed.
- Conduct product presentations and training sessions to HDFC Bank staff
 to enhance their understanding of insurance and investment products,
 and guide them for cross-selling. Provided life insurance planning and
 banking solutions to prospective and existing HDFC Bank customers.
- Act as a mediator for partners or customers related to policy issuance or with the company underwriters, arrange specialised training for partners every month for product refresher and business credit, and connect with staff for joint field business calls.
- Managed and controlled daily operations of the team. Ensure
 productivity, persistence, and performance of the team. Expanded
 current business by consistently understanding clients' changing needs
 and making appropriate recommendations.

Cluster Manager, 09/2018 - 10/2022 Care Health Inusrance - Mumbai, India

- Introduction of new product and process of distribution of CARE products in RBL Bank, ICICI Securities, and FINACRE Small Finance Bank.
- Single point of contact for queries from RBL Bank, ICICI Securities, and Fincare Small Finance Bank branch level.
- Achieve premium targets and revenue generation.
- Visiting the bank branch, meeting with the BM, and discussing business strategy.

- Responsible for motivating and generating sales from field sales managers.
- To generate fresh leads and monitor the renewals to ensure 100% conversion on such renewals.
- Prepared detailed reports on sales, stock levels, and staff performance for senior management, aiding in decision-making processes.
- Maintained detailed record of sales activities and compared trends to identify underserved areas and opportunities for improvement.

Senior Relationship Manager, 08/2017 - 09/2018 Robinhood Capital Broking - Mumbai, India

- Responsible for all types of insurance, such as life and general insurance.
- Participate in the promotional activities of the company to generate leads and achieve sales targets.
- Resolving all types of complaints, queries of existing customers, and solving service requests.

Relationship Manager, 03/2016 - 08/2017 IDBI Federal Life Insurance - Mumbai

- Scheduled, arranged and attended meetings with customers to maintain trusting and long-lasting relationships.
- Addressed and resolved customer complaints in efficient, effective and timely manner.
- Setting up meetings with new clients.
- · Looking for new sales opportunities.
- Boosted client satisfaction by monitoring and continuously improving service delivery.

Relationship Manager, 05/2014 - 03/2016 MAX Life Insurance - Mumbai

- Handled YES Bank and Max Life Insurance customers, and helped achieve the branch target.
- Implemented customer feedback mechanisms, significantly improving service delivery and client contentment.
- Built and maintained relationships with new and existing clients, while providing a high level of expertise.
- Maintained knowledge of banking products and distribution to provide optimal service support.
- Communicated regularly with clients to understand needs, evaluate current product use, and cross-sell new products.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMMERCE: ACCOUNTING,TAX,ENGLISH,COSTING,ECONOMICS, 2009 BNMA COLLEGE (FM UNIVERCITY) - ODISHA

CERTIFICATIONS

• Qualify For STAR GALAXY Award And Gala Nights.